

## **Blaise Buckland**

Software Developer

Sydney, Australia
0466 043 183 · bucklandblaise@gmail.com

⇔ GitHub, Portfolio

#### **Tech Skills**

HTML5

CSS & SCSS

JavaScript

React

Git & GitHub

Node.js

**Firebase** 

Wireframing & Figma

Jest, Enzyme, React Testing Library

Test driven development

OOP & functional programming

#### **Strengths**

Collaboration

Proactive

Teamwork & Leadership

Highly Organised

#### **Hobbies**

Board games Water sports Reading Furniture upcycling Hiking

#### **Profile**

This year, alongside my job at the Ministry of Justice, I have retrained as a software developer. In my role as a business analyst, I worked collaboratively across the organisation, engaging with colleagues to understand business needs and communicating them to the digital team. My proactive and thorough attitude and ability to build strong working relationships were key. These qualities, combined with the technical skills I have developed, will enable me to progress and excel in my career as a software developer.

### **Experience**

#### Trainee Software Developer, \_nology, Bristol

October 2021 — September 2022

Completed a self-paced bootcamp course in software development alongside full-time employment. Learning leading technologies in modern software development, with a particular focus on front-end languages. Experience in using the frameworks and tools widely used in the industry. Learning how to fix bugs myself, find answers online and when to ask a coach for advice.

#### **Key topics:**

- · Command line navigation.
- Designing and building attractive and responsive user interfaces using HTML, CSS, SCSS, BEM, Bootstrap.
- Writing clean JavaScript to build applications including games, a calculator and a morse code translator. Functional programming and OOP.
- Building React apps from scratch or based on wireframes of requirements. From drawing up component trees through to testing the finished product.
- Using APIs to provide content for React apps and allowing users to search and filter results.
- Writing thorough unit tests for projects and experience in test driven development.
- Collaborating using GitHub. Introduction to Agile and Scrum.
- Using Node.js to build an API.

#### **Business Analyst, Judicial Appointment Commission, London**

January 2022 — August 2022

I was the business analyst in a small digital team in a government department. Researching requirements for the newly implemented digital platform, engaging with stakeholders from across the organisation. Producing

detailed specifications and explaining these to the developers and product owner. Acting as the link between the digital team and the wider organisation to enable seamless collaboration and fast feedback for the developers.

#### Programme Manager, Judicial Appointments Commission, London

September 2019 — January 2022

I was responsible for the delivery of a programme of 35 recruitment campaigns per year. Allocating work to the operational teams, setting timelines for each to ensure smooth delivery and keeping the senior leadership team informed of the progress of all teams' work.

Working with officials from other government departments as well as senior judges and tribunal members to plan the recruitment processes.

#### Selection Exercise Officer, Judicial Appointments Commission, London

January 2019 — September 2019

Working in a team to plan and deliver recruitment processes to appoint judges. I engaged with external stakeholders including business partners, judges, interview panel members and candidates.

# Business Development Assistant, CooperSurgical Fertility and Genomic Solutions, London

September 2018 — December 2018

Business development assistant. I worked on a range of projects, collaborating with colleagues from teams within the UK as well as in the company's other European branches. Projects included organising customer events and creating marketing materials.

#### Receptionist, Hays, London

August 2018 — September 2018

Temporary receptionist role.

#### Warehouse Operative, Estee Lauder, Southampton

September 2017 — December 2017

#### Clinical Support, Occupational Health Consultancy Ltd, Southampton

June 2017 — August 2017

Responsible for general administrative duties as well as database management, data cleansing and creating reports for clients.

#### **Education**

#### First Class Honours BSc in Chemistry, University of Bristol

September 2014 — June 2017

Research project on greenhouse gas emissions, creating models for large data sets to create the best possible estimates of emissions from various industries.